probably since September September and
大概自九月九月
October just the beginning of this
十月刚刚开始
school year has probably been the most
学年可能是最多的
intense time in my 32 years of full-time
我32年的全职工作时间很紧张
ministry coming up on my 32nd
我的第32个部门即将到来
anniversary in December of dealing with
12月的周年纪念日处理
sexual issues both with students that
与学生的性问题
are struggling with habits and finding
正在努力寻找习惯和发现
out about those who are sexually abused
关于那些遭受性虐待的人
etc there's just been multiple issues of
刚出现了多个问题
that just in the last two months I have
就在我过去的两个月里
some statistics for you of course you
一些统计数据对你，当然你
would imagine that I'd give you some
会想象我会给你一些
statistics they're readily available on
统计他们在随时可用
this subject but as I give you these
这个主题， 但我给你这些
statistics remember that behind all
统计数据记住了所有人
these statistics are broken marriages
这些统计数字是破碎的婚姻
hurt children hurt women people with
受伤儿童伤害的妇女患有
diseases I did a little bit of research
疾病我做了一些研究
this past week on how many sexually
这个过去一周的性生活有多少
transmitted diseases there are in the
传播疾病中有
United States right now there are 25
美国现在有25个
approximately 25 and of one HPV there
大约25和一个HPV那里
are 100 different varieties listen to
是100种不同的品种听
these statistics and we ought to be
这些统计数据和我们应该是
ashamed of ourselves as Americans
以美国人为耻
because eighty-nine percent of the
因为89％
world's pornography is produced in the
世界上的色情作品是在世界上制作的
United States in one recent year 13.33
美国最近一年有13.33
billion dollars was spent on pornography
花在色情上的钱是十亿美元
260 new porn sites go online every day
260个新的色情网站每天都会 上网
some somewhere around 10 billion dollars
一些大约100亿美元
a year is spent on adult entertainment
一年花在成人娱乐上
and it's hard to get this figure we kept
我们保留这个数字很难得到
trying to do research on it but it's
试图对它进行研究，但它是
somewhere around 4.2
在4.2附近
million pornographic websites available
百万色情网站可用
on the internet right now obviously this
在互联网上，现在显然这
is a topic we need to talk about and
是我们需要谈论的话题
think about from a biblical worldview of
从圣经的世界观来思考
all the topics we've talked about this
所有我们已经谈过这个话题
is the one where I thought it would be
是我认为的那个
good to stop just for a moment and think
好好停下来片刻思考
about what do we mean by a biblical
关于圣经的含义
worldview so let's talk about viewing
世界观让我们谈谈观看
things through the lens of Scripture
通过圣经的镜头
for a moment that's what we've been
那是我们过去的那一刻
trying to do we've been working really
努力做到我们一直在努力工作
hard at that haven't we last month this
硬， 但没有我们上个月这个
month it's been about a biblical
一个月它是关于圣经的
worldview so I like to use my glasses
世界观所以我喜欢用我的眼镜
since we're talking about lenses I'll
因为我们正在谈论镜头我会
use my glasses as an illustration when I
我用眼镜作为插图
think about biblical worldview I think
我想，想想圣经的世界观
about whatever the topic is because we
关于这个话题是什么， 因为我们
believe in the doctrine of inerrancy the
相信无误的教义
doctrine of inerrancy basically says
无误的学说基本上说
this that whatever subject that
无论那个主题是什么
scripture addresses not just spiritual
经文不仅仅是属灵的
matters but whatever subject that
问题但无论是主题
scripture addresses it is the authority
经文说明它是权威
and it must be accurate in Aaron without
在没有的情况下，它必须在Aaron中是准确的
error and here's the logical reason why
错误和这里的逻辑原因
because we say it's the inspired Word of
因为我们说这是灵感的话语
God
神
that means it's God breathed so if the
这意味着， 如果是的话，上帝会呼吸
Word of God is God breathed then any
任何上帝的话语都是上帝的呼吸
subject that means coming right out of
主题意味着出来
the mouth of God it's living an act of
上帝的口，它的生活是一种行为
Hebrews 4:12 if the Word of God is from
希伯来书4:12 如果神的话语来自
the mouth of God if he's the author
如果他是作者 ，那么上帝的口
altima author of Scripture then any
圣经中的Altima笔者 再任
subject he addresses has to be accurate
主题他必须准确
or else God's a liar so the doctrine of
或者上帝是个骗子，所以是教义
inerrancy teaches that whatever subject
inerrancy教导任何主题
that scripture addresses it becomes the
那经文解决它成为了
authority through which we look at life
我们看待生活的权威
so we call that on our campus a biblical
所以我们在校园里称之为 圣经
worldview so the lenses through which I
世界观所以镜头通过我
look at life are the lenses of biblical
看看生活是圣经的镜头
principles now just in general for
原则现在只是一般的
counseling in what I'm looking at humans
在我正在看人类时提供咨询
so if I'm looking at you what do I
所以，如果我看着你，我该怎么做
see if I look through secular
看看我是否通过世俗观察
psychological lenses their world view
心理透镜他们的世界观
what do I see people damaged by their
我怎么看待被他们伤害的人
experience there is no God there is no
经验没有上帝没有
sin nature etc but if I look through
罪恶的自然等，但如果我看透
biblical lenses
圣经镜片
I see biblical principles like Genesis 3
我看到像创世纪3这样的圣经原则
is real were made in the image of God
是真实的是在上帝的形象
were made to be worshippers of the true
被认为是真正的崇拜者
and living God but we end up worshipping
和活着的上帝，但我们最终崇拜
the wrong things etc so on this subject
关于这个问题的错误的事情等等
we're gonna look at this subject of
我们要看看这个主题
sexuality and there's all kinds of ways
性和有各种各样的方式
that this could go but it's gonna be in
这可能会发生，但它会进入
general just a general conversation
一般只是一般性对话
about what does the Bible have to say
关于圣经有什么要说的
about sexuality but in particular the
关于性，但特别是
focus since this is where most of our
重点，因为这是我们大多数人的地方
counseling will be will be about the
咨询将是关于
husband and wife relationship even
甚至 夫妻关系
though there's all kinds of other
虽然还有其他各种各样的东西
directions that this should go I just
这应该是我的方向
thought it would be good to talk about a
认为这将是很好的 谈
biblical worldview and what does a
圣经的世界观和什么是
biblical worldview mean and the Bible is
圣经的世界观意味着圣经
not ashamed at all to talk about this
谈论这件事并不感到羞耻
subject here's some interesting quotes
这里有一些有趣的引用
that I found recommending a book and you
我发现推荐一本书和你
have a number of really good resources
有一些非常好的资源
on the last page and when we get there
在最后一页，当我们到达那里
I'm gonna highlight a couple of them
我要突出其中几个
that I've found really helpful but one
我发现真的很有帮助但只有一个
of the ones that I think every person in
那些我认为每个人的人
this room ought to read is called sex
这个房间应该读的叫做性
and the supremacy of Christ by John
和 约翰的基督至高无上
Piper if listen to the rationale here
派珀如果听取这里的理由
for a little bit
一点点
Romans 11:36 says everything is from him
罗马书11:36说一切都来自他
so from him through him and back to him
所以从他身边经过他并回到他身边
are all things
万物都是
to him be the glory for ever and ever
对他 来说永远是荣耀
amen
阿门
well that all things doesn't that
好吧，所有的事情都没有
include sexuality it's from him it's
包括性，这是他的意思
through him and it's back to him so a
通过他，又回到了他这么一个
couple of people that were recommending
几个推荐的人
this book sex in the supremacy of Christ
这本书性在基督的至高无上
I found that their their recommendations
我发现了他们的建议
were quite insightful this one is from
非常有见地， 这是来自
world
世界
magazine if you're familiar with world
杂志，如果你熟悉世界
magazine one of the writers for world
杂志是世界作家之一
magazine
杂志
recommending sex and the supremacy of
推荐性和至高无上的
Christ said in a culture that's
基督在一种文化中说道
desperately asking sex to be the Alpha
拼命地要求性别成为阿尔法
and Omega this book shows how sex is
和欧米茄这本书展示了性是怎样的
better when Christ is Alpha and Omega I
当基督是阿尔法和欧米茄时更好
appreciated that sex and the supremacy
赞赏性和至高无上的
of Christ and that's what this
基督，这就是这个
presentation in essence is what we're
介绍本质上是我们的
going to be talking about how do we
谈论我们怎么样
think about sex biblically as an act of
把圣经中的性视为一种行为
worship to God and I know I mean even
敬拜上帝，我知道我的意思是甚至
just saying those words we go
只说我们说的那些话
that is strange thinking in American
那是美国人的奇怪想法
culture sex as an act of worship to God
文化性是一种崇拜上帝的行为
but that phrase are all things implies
但那句话都是暗示的
that again first Corinthians 10:31
哥林多前书10:31再一次
whether we eat or drink or whatever we
我们是否吃或喝或任何我们
do do all to the glory of God here's
尽力做到这里的上帝的荣耀
another one maybe you'll recognize this
另一个也许你会认识到这一点
name Nancy Lee Dumas she said this I
她说Nancy Lee Dumas这个我
cannot think of any gift of God that has
想不出有上帝的任何礼物
been more abused and misused than that
被滥用和滥用比这更多
of sex what was intended to be a listen
性的意图是什么是一个听
to her wording a stunning pure earthly
她的措辞令人惊叹的纯洁尘世
picture of an amazing heavenly eternal
一幅惊人的天国永恒的画面
reality has been perverted into an
现实已经变成了现实
alluring but false God that is in fact a
诱惑，但虚假的上帝，实际上是一个
grotesque caricature of the true God
真神的怪诞漫画
they are calling us and that's the
他们在呼唤我们，那就是
writers of the book sex in the supremacy
这本书的作家在至高无上的性行为
of Christ they are calling us to bring
基督他们在呼召我们带来
our thoughts and our lives into
我们的思想和我们的生活进入
captivity to the supremacy of Christ and
被囚禁到基督和至高无上的地位
listen to our next wording because this
听听我们的下一个措辞，因为这个
is hard for a lot of Christians to
对很多基督徒来说很难
really get your mind wrapped around this
真的让你的思绪缠绕在这上面
type of thinking about your relationship
关于你的关系的思考方式
with Christ they are calling us to bring
与基督一同呼召我们带来
our thoughts and our lives into
我们的思想和我们的生活
captivity to the supremacy of Christ and
被囚禁到基督和至高无上的地位
to reflect our ravishment with our
以反映我们与我们的ravishment
heavenly bridegroom in our sexuality now
现在 我们性欲中的天上新郎
think about the biblical principle
想一想圣经的原则
behind that if our relationship
如果我们的关系背后
with a husband and wife is a picture of
与丈夫和妻子是一张照片
Christ's relationship with the church
基督与教会的关系
and sex is this very passionate thing
和性是这个非常有激情的事情
that a husband and wife enjoy with one
丈夫和妻子一个人享受
another it is a picture of the the depth
另一个是深度的图片
of relationship that they're supposed to
关系的是他们应该
be in relationship with Christ whether
与基督有关系
we eat or drink or whatever we do do all
我们吃或喝或做我们做的所有事情
to the glory of God
为了上帝的荣耀
this could take all kinds of directions
这可以采取各种方向
there's all kinds of ways that it could
它有各种各样的方式
go especially in light of pornography
特别是根据色情内容
homosexuality sex trafficking but again
同性恋性交易再次发生
I'm gonna focus on the big picture view
我将专注于全局视图
of sexuality and then in particular
性的，然后特别是
emphasize marriage so point one in your
强调婚姻，所以指出你的婚姻
notes sex in marriage is pure and holy
注意婚姻中的性行为是纯洁圣洁的
that's a radical statement right off the
这是一个激进的声明
bat for our culture we're going to be in
为我们的文化蝙蝠，我们将要进入
particular looking at two main passages
特别是看两个主要段落
and there'll be another few passages
而且会有另外几段
that are really important to build our
这对我们来说非常重要
our lenses that we're looking at our
我们正在看我们的镜头
worldview
世界观
1st Corinthians 7 will be a main one
哥林多前书7章将是主要的
proverbs chapter 5 will be another main
谚语第5章将是另一个主要内容
passage but let's just think about this
通过，但让我们考虑一下
in general for a moment this takes an
总的来说这需要一个
act of faith because this point sex in
信仰的行为， 因为这点性
marriage is pure and holy if sex is
如果性生活，婚姻是纯洁和神圣的
portrayed on television in marriage it's
这是婚姻中描绘的电视节目
probably portrayed as something that is
大概描绘成的东西，是
boring not exciting at all
无聊不精彩可言
the way that the scriptures picture the
经文描绘的方式
husband and wife sexual relationship
夫妻性关系
though is that as the years progress the
虽然这是随着岁月的进步而来的
hug and you're growing more and more
拥抱，你越来越多
together in that one flesh relationship
在一个肉体的关系中
that the sexual relationship actually
实际上是性关系
gets better that's a really radical
变得更好，这是一个非常激进的
thought for our culture to think that
为我们的文化思考这一点
the best sexual relationship if a
如果是最好的性关系
husband and wife are growing in intimacy
丈夫和妻子在亲密中成长
and as soul mates with one another
和彼此的灵魂交配
member again you don't find your
会员再次你找不到你的
soulmate you grow as soulmates that the
灵魂伴侣你成长为灵魂伴侣
best sexual relationship if we're
如果我们是最好的性关系
following biblical type of thinking the
以下圣经型思维的
way God designed it is after 50 not
方式上帝设计的，它是50后 不
before 50 as a husband and wife are
50作为丈夫和妻子是前
growing together sex in marriage is pure
在婚姻中共同成长是纯粹的
and holy let's we have to do a lot of
而且， 我们必须做很多事情
rethinking here don't we because of what
在这里重新思考我们不是因为什么
our culture is saying so a couple of sub
我们的文化是这样说的几个子
points it was created by God before sin
指出它是在罪之前由上帝创造的
Genesis 1:27 is a verse that's not in
创世记1:27是一节不在的经文
your notes but 127 and 126 27 and 28 or
你的笔记，但127和12627和28或
the verses where God told them to fill
上帝告诉他们填补的经文
the earth obviously involved in plying a
地球显然涉及到一个
sexual relationship but chapter 2 the
性关系，但第2章
end of the chapter tells us that they
本章的结尾告诉我们他们
are to be in one flesh with each other
彼此要有一个肉体
and they were both naked and not ashamed
他们都是赤身裸体而不是羞耻
what happened chapter 3 tells us then
然后第3章告诉我们
because of sin and it emphasizes this
因为罪，它强调这一点
chapter 2 ends with they're naked and
第二章结束时他们是赤身裸体的
not ashamed
不以为耻
chapter 3 one of the first things that
第3章首先要做的事情之一
happens after sin is now they're naked
在罪恶之后发生，现在他们是赤身裸体
and ashamed something happens in chapter
并且惭愧的事情发生在章节中
3 so that the sexual relationship gets
3以便性关系得到
perverted but before the fall it's
变态但秋天之前它的
created by God this is a good gift of
由上帝创造，这是一个很好的礼物
God and even after sin enters it is
上帝甚至在罪进入之后就是
still called good look at Hebrews
仍然好好看看希伯来书
chapter 13 if you would let's turn there
第13章如果你愿意转过来
so even after the fall God calls the
所以即使在堕落之后，上帝也会召唤
sexual relationship honorable in
性关系光荣的
marriage boy do we need to emphasize
婚姻男孩做我们需要强调
that Hebrews 13:4 love this verse let
希伯来书13：4喜欢这节经文
marriage be held in honor among all and
婚姻是为了纪念所有人和
let the marriage bed be undefiled look
让婚床看起来没有瑕疵
at the next phrase for fornicators and
在fornicators 和 。的下一个短语
adulterers God will judge and I think
奸夫上帝会审判，我想
it's interesting to think of this verse
它认为这首诗的有趣
in light of even the next verse let your
即使下一节经文也让你的
character be free from the love of
性格是免于爱的
money being content with what you have
金钱满足于你拥有的东西
for he himself has said I will never
因为他自己说我永远不会
leave you nor forsake you as I mentioned
如我所说， 离开你也不离弃你
a few minutes ago believing that sex in
几分钟前相信性行为
marriage is God's design I said that
婚姻是上帝的设计我说的
takes an act of faith and telling our
采取信仰行为并告诉我们
kids today that by faith they need to
今天的孩子，他们需要凭信心
believe that God has their best interest
相信上帝有他们的最大利益
in mind and it will be in your best
记住，它将是你最好的
interest if you will keep yourself pure
感兴趣， 如果你保持自己纯洁
until marriage because you will have
直到结婚， 因为你会有
better sexual relationship in marriage
婚姻中更好的性关系
that is an act of faith for our
这是对我们的信仰行为
generation for a younger generation and
为年轻一代而生
for our country right now to say there
对于我们国家现在说那里
is superior and here's the idea there is
是优越的，这是有的想法
superior pleasure in sex not our in sex
性爱的优越感，而不是性爱
in marriage not outside of marriage that
在婚姻中不是婚姻之外的那种
takes a big step of faith for our
为我们的信仰迈出了重要的一步
culture to believe that if I with if I
文化相信如果我和我在一起
will control myself and exhibit
将控制自己和展览
self-control there will be better sex in
自我控制会有更好的性生活
marriage that takes an act of faith
婚姻是需要信心的行动
point C any other view is sinful to
C点任何其他观点都是有罪的
think of sex outside of marriage as
想到婚外性行为
legitimate any other view or that it's
合法的任何其他观点或它是
okay for me to withhold myself from a
好吧，我可以保留自己
person in marriage any other view is
婚姻中任何其他观点的人
sinful it's supposed to be this
有罪它应该是这样的
passionate reflection of Christ loving
热爱基督爱的反映
relationship with his church intense
与他的教会关系紧张
passionate love that's done as an act of
热情的爱，这是作为一种行为
worship saint randy alcorn said this
崇拜圣人兰迪·奥尔康说，这
great quote sex is a wonderful gift from
伟大的引用性是一个很棒的礼物
God but it makes a terrible idle brutal
上帝，但它是一个可怕的闲置残酷
and unyielding in the misery it inflicts
它所遭受的苦难中不屈不挠
it promises really big but it doesn't
它承诺真的很大，但事实并非如此
deliver what it promises so let me ask
实现它所承诺的， 所以让我问一下
you a couple of questions
你有几个问题
remember last night's presentation that
记得昨晚的演讲
I believe the heart is about worship and
我相信内心是关于崇拜和
that the the bottom-line view of the
那个底线视图
Christian life is that everything is to
基督徒的生活就是一切
be done as an act
作为一种行为
of worship if you start to buy into that
如果你开始购买那个崇拜
philosophy that the Christian life is
基督徒生活的哲学
primarily about worship and that life is
主要是关于崇拜和生活
about worship and I was made to be a
关于崇拜，我被认为是一个
worshiper then do you view sexual
崇拜者然后你看性
relations in marriage to be as Holy as
婚姻关系如同圣洁一样
praying that's a stretch for a lot of
祈祷这是一个很大的延伸
people do you view it as holy as reading
人们你认为它像阅读一样神圣
the Bible and giving or teaching a
圣经，给予或教导
Sunday School class everything whether
星期日学校班级一切都是
you eat or drink or whatever you do do
你吃或喝或做任何事
all to the glory of God
一切都归功于上帝的荣耀
active worship the sexual relationship
积极崇拜性关系
as an act of worship point to sex is not
作为一种崇拜指向性的行为不是
the basis of marriage that's another
婚姻的基础是另一个
radical statement marriage is not first
激进的声明婚姻不是第一位的
and foremost a physical union I meant to
最重要的是物理结合中，我打算
bring this up back when we were talking
当我们说话时把它带回来
about the purposes of marriage but it
关于婚姻的目的，但它
fits in well here when does the marriage
婚姻什么时候适合这里
take place does the marriage take place
发生不婚 发生
when the vows are made and the pastor
当誓言和牧师
says by the authority invested in me I
我投资的权威说
now pronounce you husband and wife or
现在宣布你的丈夫或妻子或
does the marriage really take place on
婚姻真的发生在
the honeymoon when they have sex for the
蜜月时，他们发生性关系的
first time well because of my view of
第一次因为我的观点很好
marriage in that it's a covenant
婚姻，因为它是一个契约
relationship and that it's primarily the
关系，它主要是
sacred commitment I believe that the
神圣的承诺我相信
marriage takes place it really takes
婚姻发生真的需要
place during the ceremony when the vows
仪式期间誓言的地方
take place before God and they make a
发生在上帝之前，他们做了一个
commitment to one another and the pastor
对彼此和牧师的 承诺
says I now pronounce you husband and
说我现在说你丈夫和
wife the Covenant has been made the
妻子的盟约已经成为了
sexual relationship later on in the day
当天晚些时候的性关系
is the picture the symbolic picture of
是图片的象征性图片
what took place earlier in the day as
当天早些时候发生的事情
I've mentioned already earlier today we
我今天早些时候已经提到过了
believe sex is at the end of the
相信性是在最后
intimacy chain not the beginning of the
亲密关系链不是开始
intimacy chain sex is not or marriage is
亲密关系性别不是婚姻或婚姻
not primarily about the sexual
主要不是关于 性
relationship the sexual relationship is
性关系是关系
the outgrowth of all that the marriage
所有婚姻的产物
represents now a couple of points and
代表现在几个百分点和
then I want to have you add something to
那么我想让你添加一些东西
your notes that I think that I think
你认为我认为你的笔记
will be really helpful in this regard
在这方面会非常有帮助
that sex is at the end of the intimacy
性是在亲密关系的最后
chain first point under this Jesus
链在这个耶稣之下的第一点
settled this issue John chapter 4 woman
解决了这个问题约翰第4章的女人
at the well we won't take the time to
在井边我们不会花时间去
turn there but the woman at the well he
转过来， 但那个女人在他身边
says go get your husband she's she says
说她去找你的丈夫，她说
I have no husband and then Lord says
我没有丈夫， 然后主说
you're right you speak truthfully you've
你是对你说话如实你已经
had five husbands and the man you're
有五个丈夫和那个男人
living with is not is not your husband
与生活在一起不是不是你的丈夫
so in other words she's living with a
换句话说，她和一个人生活在一起
man obviously they're having sexual
男人显然他们有性行为
relationships or relationship with one
与一个人的关系或关系
another and the Lord is saying you're
另一个，主正在说你
not married so just because people are
没有结婚，只因为人们
living together and they're being
生活在一起， 他们正在生活
intimate with one another doesn't mean
彼此亲密并不意味着
that they're married point B unity in
他们结婚了B点团结
marriage is about much more than sex I
婚姻是比性爱我大概更
had a couple that I was counseling one
有一对我正在辅导一个
time and I've probably had other men
时间，我可能还有其他男人
that thought this they just weren't
他们认为这不是他们
brave enough to express it but this one
勇敢地表达它，但这一个
man was very brave and he said if I
男人很勇敢，他说如果我
could just get her back in bed with me
可以让她和我 一起回到床上
everything would be great
一切都会很棒
and I thought wow how naive is that and
而且我觉得哇这多么天真
there's probably been some other men
可能还有其他一些男人
that have thought that you just didn't
认为你没有
say it he was just bold and in saying it
说它只是大胆而且说出来
mm-hmm
毫米-HMM
there was a reason why she didn't want
有一个原因，她不想要
to be in bed with him there was a lot of
与他在床上有很多
stuff in that marriage listen to this
婚姻中的东西听这个
for a moment what leads to that type of
什么导致这种类型的
intimacy and big question my heart just
亲密和大问题我的心
breaks for all of these people that are
减免所有这些人是的
searching for in-depth relationships
寻找深入的关系
looking for something whatever it is
寻找的东西不管它是什么
with pornography or all of the other
与色情或其他所有
different sexual expressions I think
我认为不同的性表达
that a lot of it has to do with intimacy
，很多它与亲密关系做
so let's think about for a moment what
让我们考虑一下什么
leads to true intimacy a big big topic
导致真正的亲密关系成为一个重大的话题
here but let me just give you a couple
在这里， 但让我给你一对
of quick thoughts related to this if sex
如果发生性关系，那么快速思考与此有关
is
是
the end of the intimacy chain when I'm
亲密关系的结束，当我
doing marriage counseling or premarital
做婚姻咨询或婚前
counseling
辅导服务
I teach couples that there are six
我教夫妇有六个
relationship skills that lead to healthy
关系技巧， 导致健康
relationships
关系
here are the six relationship skills and
这里有六种关系技巧和
we're trying to address what leads to
我们正试图解决导致的问题
true intimacy intimacy is not just about
真正亲密的亲密关系并非如此
you were physical with one another it's
你是彼此身体健康的
a lot deeper than that well number one
很多比以及头号更深
it has to do with communication are you
它是你的沟通做
keeping the four communication
保持四个沟通
principles that we talked about earlier
我们前面谈到的原则
today are you communicating with one
今天你有一个沟通
another are you involved in one
另一个是你参与其中一个
another's lives and you understand
另一个人的生活，你明白
what's going on in each other's lives
在彼此的生活中发生了什么
and that takes communication are you
而且需要沟通的是你
resolving conflict not just talking
解决冲突而不仅仅是说话
about conflicts a lot of couples do that
关于冲突很多夫妻都这样做
but conflict resolution you know - how
但你知道冲突解决方案- 如何
to actually bring your conflicts to
真正把你的冲突
resolution you come to agreements and
决议你达成协议和
you move on and you're not living with
你前进，你 不活
all kinds of issues from the past that
从以往的各种问题是
you can never come to agreement on
你永远不能达成协议
number three you're honoring and serving
第三，你很荣幸和服务
each other on a regular basis
对方定期
Philippians chapter 2 or John 13 you're
腓立比书第2章或约翰福音13章你是
washing one another's feet or number
洗涤彼此的脚或数字
four good relationships take time you're
四个良好的关系需要时间
investing in the relationship by
通过投资关系
investing time or number five I'm gonna
投资时间或五号我会
use the word worship but I need to
使用崇拜这个词， 但我需要
clarify what I mean by worship worship
澄清我崇拜崇拜的意思
you are walking with the Lord together I
你和主同行，我
often ask couples when I'm doing
在我做的时候经常问夫妻
marriage counseling and this is a trick
婚姻咨询，这是一个伎俩
kind of tricky I ask how often do you
棘手的一种请问你多久
pray together other than meals and it's
除了饭菜之外，我们一起祈祷
really interesting I asked that question
真有意思我问了这个问题
how often do you pray together other
你经常和其他人一起祷告
than meals and I'll get the answer well
吃饭，我会得到答案
we pray together when we are about to
当我们即将到来时，我们一起祈祷
eat well I just ask you how often do you
吃得好我只是问你多久一次
pray together because they're feeling
一起祈祷，因为他们有感觉
really bad about this time that they
他们这次非常糟糕
don't pray together any other time other
其他任何时候都不要一起祈祷
than meals are you walking with the Lord
与你同餐，你与主同行
together do you have common religious
你们有共同的宗教信仰吗？
convictions are you headed the same way
你是以同样的方式定罪的
spiritually that's what I mean by
在精神上，这就是我的意思
worship
崇拜
and then do you understand husband and
然后你了解丈夫和
wife roles
妻子的角色
what's the husband's supposed to do
丈夫应该怎么做
what's the wife's supposed to do how do
什么是妻子应该怎么做
the kids fit into the picture we've
孩子们适合我们的照片
talked about roles now think about the
谈到角色， 现在想想
logic here if we're communicating and
如果我们正在沟通和 这里的逻辑
we're resolving conflict and we're
我们正在解决冲突，我们正在解决
serving one another regularly and we're
经常互相服务，我们是
investing in our relationship through
通过投资我们的关系
time we're walking with the Lord
我们和主同行的时候了
together and we understand our roles I
在一起，我们明白我们的角色我
don't think there's gonna be problems in
不认为会 是在问题
the sexual relationship you're you're
性关系你是你
gonna enjoy being together you're gonna
会喜欢和你在一起
want to be together and unless there's
想要在一起，除非有
some type of other physical issue going
某种其他物理问题
on that's what I mean by intimacy add to
在这就是我所说的亲密关系
that then what we talked about last
那就是我们最后谈到的
night that you understand your spouse's
晚上，你了解你的配偶
heart you understand their motives maybe
你明白他们的动机也许是心
you understand that your spouse has
你明白你的配偶有
control tendencies but you say I love
控制倾向，但你说我喜欢
you anyway and love becomes more than
无论如何，爱变得更多
just I love you because of who you are
我爱你，因为你是谁
but I love you in spite of who you are
但我爱你，不管你是谁
and if that's true and you understand
如果这是真的，你明白了
your spouse's heart even the bad
你配偶的心脏甚至是坏事
motivations of the heart and you're
心灵的动机和你
working on these six relationship skills
致力于这六种关系技巧
I don't think you're gonna have to worry
我不认为你会担心
about the sexual relationship that is
关于性关系是
true that leads to true intimacy so
这是真的， 因此导致真正的亲密关系
point be there unity in marriage is more
点是有统一的婚姻更
than sex sex is at the end of the
性生活比性生活还要早
intimacy chain but the sexual
亲密关系但性
relationship is still very important
关系仍然非常重要
probably other than the Song of Solomon
可能不是所罗门之歌
the most explicit book that's ever been
有史以来最明确的书
written in the evangelical church is
写在福音派教会的是
intended for pleasure
用于娱乐
by dr. ed wheat he's not ashamed to talk
由博士。 小麦他说话并不羞耻
about whatever the issues are related to
有关的任何问题都涉及到
sexuality but he was so frustrated as a
性欲， 但他是如此沮丧
physician dr. ed wheat he was so
医师博士ed 小麦他是这样的
frustrated by the world's perspective on
对世界的看法感到沮丧
sexuality that he decided that he wanted
性欲，他决定他想要
to write a book from a biblical
从圣经写一本书
perspective on sexuality and that's
关于性的观点和那个
where intended for pleasure came let me
有意为快乐的地方让我
tell you about another book
告诉你另一本书
that I read recently and I thought it
我最近读过的，我想到了
was good and noticed how thick it is you
好，并且注意到它是你有多厚
can do this one sex romance and the
可以做到这一个性爱浪漫和
glory of God by CJ Mohini and his wife
CJ莫希尼和他的妻子对上帝的荣耀
Carolyn Mohini they did a good job sex
Carolyn Mohini他们做得很好
romance and the glory of God next point
浪漫和下一点神的荣耀
here's the Christian worldview is at its
这是基督教世界观的基础
best this is directly opposite of the
最好这是与之相反的
secular viewpoint the primary goal of
世俗观点的主要目标
the sexual relationship is giving what's
性关系正在给予什么
the world's perspective the world's
全球的角度来看世界
perspective the cultures perspective
透视文化视角
would be what can I get you to do for me
将是我可以让你为我做什么
instead of the christ-like servant
而不是像基督一样的仆人
attitude of how can I serve you what
我怎么能为你服务的态度
gives you pleasure let's go back and
给你带来快乐让我们回去吧
this the idea of sexuality does not come
这个性欲的想法并没有到来
out at all
完全没有
in Philippians 2 but this is the
在腓立比书2但这是
Christian worldview turn to Philippians
基督教世界观转向腓立比人
2 if you would remember what our Lord
2如果你还记得我们的主
said it's better to give than to receive
说给予比接受更好
and here's what happens isn't it true
而这里发生的事情并非如此
that when you give and you're giving and
当你给予和你给予和
you're giving you find fulfillment in
你给你找履行在
serving another person that's the lord's
服务于另一个人的主人
perspective it's better to give than to
透视，给予比给予更好
receive
接收
I think how beautiful it is a wife is
我觉得它是多么美丽的一个妻子
focusing on that how can I give the
聚焦于如何我可以给
husband is focusing on how to give and
丈夫正专注于如何给予和
you're both fighting against your flesh
你们都在与自己的肉体作斗争
and the natural fleshly tendency is how
自然的肉体倾向是怎样的
can I get you to do what I want you to
我可以让你做我想要你做的事
do that would make me feel good and
这样做会让我感觉良好，
you're both fighting against that and
你们都在反对这一点
you're both focusing on giving don't you
你们都专注于不给你
think there'll be incredible mutual
认为会有令人难以置信的共同点
satisfaction that occurs in that husband
在丈夫身上发生的满足感
and wife relationship that's the
和妻子的关系就是这样
Christian ethic coming out I thought it
基督教的道德出现我想到了
would be good just to re refresh our
将是一件好事只是重新刷新我们
memories about what Philippians chapter
关于腓立比章节的回忆
2 said I was asked a number of years ago
2说，有人问我若干年前
some students asked me if we backed you
有些学生问我是否支持你
into a corner and you could only use one
进入一个角落，你只能使用一个
passage of Scripture to save marriages
通过圣经以挽救婚姻
what would be the passage of Scripture
什么是圣经的通过
that you would go to and what would be
那你会去，会是什么
the biblical principle to save Mary
拯救玛丽 的圣经原则
and I said that would be really easy it
而且我说那会非常容易
would be Philippians chapter 2
将是腓立比书第2章
Philippians chapter 2 is the core of the
腓立比书2的核心
Christian ethic about what it means to
关于它意味着什么的基督教伦理
live the Christian life learning to
过基督徒生活学习
serve other people
为别人服务
Philippians 2 I'll start reading with
腓2我开始阅读
verse 3 do nothing that would include
第3节什么也不做
sexuality from selfishness or empty
自私或空虚的性欲
conceit but with humility of mind let
自负而是心灵的谦卑让
each of you regard one another as more
你们每个人都认为彼此更多
important than himself do not merely
重要的不是自己做的不只是
look out for your own personal interests
注意自己的个人兴趣
but also for the interests of others
但也为了他人的利益
have this attitude and here's the
有这种态度，这就是
ultimate example of this type of ethic
这种道德的最终例子
have this attitude in yourselves which
你自己有这种态度
was also in Christ Jesus who although he
也是在基督耶稣里，虽然他
existed in the form of God did not
在形式存在的上帝没有
regard equality with God a thing to be
认为与上帝平等是一件好事
grasped but emptied himself so empty
抓住但是把自己倒空了
yourself in relationship with your
你自己与你的关系
spouse taking the form of a bondservant
采取债权人形式的配偶
being made in the likeness of men being
正是以男人的形象造的
found in appearance as a man he humbled
在外表上发现 他是一个谦卑的男人
himself by becoming obedient to the
自己变得顺从了
point of death even death on a cross and
在十字架和死亡甚至死亡的点
then God honors him because of this God
然后上帝因为这位上帝而尊敬他
highly exalted him and bestowed on him
高举他并赐予他
the name which is above every name the
这是每一个之上的名的
primary goal the sexual relationship is
性关系的主要目标
providing sexual satisfaction for one's
为一个人提供性满足感
spouse now let's go to 1st Corinthians
配偶现在让我们去哥林多前书
chapter 7 and I mentioned 1st
第7章和我提到第1
Corinthians 7 in proverbs 5 are going to
箴言5中的哥林多前书7章要去
be two key passages this is also taught
这是两个关键的段落，这也是教导
this idea of serving your spouse is
为配偶服务的想法是
taught in 1st Corinthians chapter 7 I
在哥林多前书第7章教导我
was driving through the this is an East
正在开车穿过这是一个东方
Coast illustration and many of the old
海岸例证和许多老
towns on the East Coast they have a
他们在东海岸的城镇有一个
center circle and you drive around the
中心圈，你开车绕过
towns in the town square around the
镇周围的城镇广场
center circle and I was driving around
中心圈，我在开车
the center circle in a town in
中心圆的镇
Pennsylvania near where I grew up and
宾夕法尼亚州附近我长大的地方
there was a bookstore there get the name
那里有一家书店得到了这个名字
of this bookstore it was called the
这家书店被称为
Corinthian Christian bookstore
科林斯基督教书店
and I thought wow who and I was only a
而且我觉得哇，我和谁只是一个
teenager at that time and I thought who
当时的少年，我想到了谁
in their right mind would call their
在他们正确的心灵会打电话给他们
Christian bookstore the Corinthian
基督教书店科林斯
Christian bookstore this church has a
这个教堂有一个基督教书店
boatload of problems and here's another
船上的问题，这是另一个
example chapter 7 they're dealing with
他们正在处理的例子第七章
sexual issues and it seems like part of
性问题似乎是其中的一部分
what's going on there they wrote a
那里发生了什么， 他们写了一个
letter to Paul and Paul's addressing all
写给保罗和保罗的信
their questions and they just must have
他们的问题，他们必须有
sent him a whole list of questions and
送他的问题，整个列表 和
notice the first phrase of verse 1 he
注意第1节的第一句话
says now concerning so that's the main
现在说关于这是主要的
phrase in first Corinthians now
现在在科林蒂安的第一个短语
concerning and he addresses the next
关于和他解决了下一个问题
question and it seems like one of the
问题，它似乎是其中之一
questions that they may have been
他们可能有过的问题
addressing was this Paul now that we're
现在解决这个保罗，我们是
believers should we do vows divorce our
我们应该誓言离婚我们的信徒
unbelieving spouse and get remarried to
不信的配偶， 并再婚
a Christian who might have the same
一个可能有同样基督徒的基督徒
convictions that I think 1st Corinthians
我认为哥林多前书的 信念
7 is one of the most difficult chapters
7是最困难的章节之一
in the Bible especially the New
在圣经中特别是新的
Testament to understand you have really
遗嘱理解你真的
have to understand and think about
必须要了解和思考
what's going on in the context and what
在上下文中发生了什么以及发生了什么
might have been the questions that were
可能是那些问题
asked of Paul that he's giving answers
保罗问他正在给出答案
for here in 1st Corinthians 7 now with
现在在哥林多前书7号
that in mind as we looked at the context
考虑到背景 ，请记住这一点
Paul's answering questions maybe that
保罗回答问题可能就是这样
was one of the questions that was posed
是的这是所提出的问题之一
to him and remembered in Corinth there
对他而言，在哥林多那里记得
was a lot of sexual idolatry going on so
很多性偶像崇拜都是如此
that's all behind what's going on going
这一切都落后于正在发生的事情
into addressing these questions in 1st
在第1节解决这些问题
Corinthians 7 he then says this now
哥林多前书7 然后他说了这个
concerning the things about which you
关于你的事情
wrote it is good for a man not to touch
写道，对一个不接触的人来说这是件好事
a woman I think he's talking about in
一个女人， 我认为他是在谈论
the flow of the passage here's one of
这段经文的流动是其中之一
those difficult things right off the bat
那些困难的事情立即开始
what does it mean not to touch a woman
什么意思不触摸女人
that was actually quoted at the
这实际上引用了
Christian school that I attended why
基督教学校，我参加了为什么
boys weren't allowed to touch girls not
男孩们不允许接触女孩
to touch a woman I think in the flow of
触摸一个女人，我想在流动
the passage means remain unmarried
通道意味着未婚
you can take that or leave it that's
你可以接受或留下它
just opinion there but because of
只是认为有，但由于
immoralities let each have his own wife
不道德让每个人都有自己的妻子
and let each woman have her own husband
让每个女人都有自己的丈夫
let the husband fulfill his duty to his
让丈夫履行他的职责
wife and likewise also the wife to her
妻子也是她的妻子
husband the wife does not have authority
丈夫妻子没有权力
over her own body but the husband does
在她自己的身体，但丈夫
and likewise also the husband does not
丈夫也没有
have authority over his own body but the
对自己的身体 有权威 但是
wife does stop depriving one another
妻子不停止剥夺彼此
except for by agreement for a time that
除了一时间一致认为 ，
you may devote yourselves to prayer
你可以献身祷告
that's normally not the reason why I run
这通常不是我跑的原因
into in marriage counseling why people
进入婚姻咨询为什么是人
are withholding themselves from each
从每个人身上扣留
other wish it was that be interesting
其他人希望这很有意思
and come together again less Satan tempt
并再次聚集在一起，减少撒旦的诱惑
you because of your lack of self-control
你是因为你缺乏自制力
let's go through some principles here we
让我们来看看我们的一些原则
are called to fulfill verse 3 we're
被称为履行第3节 我们
given a command to give ourselves fully
给予一个完全放弃自己的命令
completely without reluctance and
完全没有不情愿和
hesitation or inhibition fulfill my body
犹豫或抑制满足了我的身体
does not belong to me my wife's body
不属于我我妻子的身体
does not belong to her I am to give
不属于她我要给
remember Philippians chapter 2 I am to
记得腓立比书第2章我要
give my body to my wife my wife belongs
把我的身体交给我妻子所属的妻子
or my wife's body belongs to me my body
或者我妻子的遗体属于我的身体
belongs to her is the Christian
属于她的是基督徒
worldview this is my duty next point
这个世界观是我的责任下一个点
means a responsibility with the idea of
意味着有责任
doing good to the other person I am
做好其他的人，我
called to fulfill my duty so obviously
因此显然要求履行我的职责
from a Christian perspective this is not
从基督教的角度来看，这不是
a begrudging duty and I'm going to
乞讨责任，我要去
address some myths here in a little bit
稍微解决一些神话
and one of those myths that I think of
和我想到的那些神话之一
right now is that a wife says it's I
现在是妻子说是我
just have to do my duty
只是要履行我的职责
and some people think some women think
有些人认为有些女性会这样想
women don't get sexual satisfaction God
女人不会得到性满足的上帝
did not design women the myth would be
没有设计女性的神话会是什么
God did not design women for sexual
上帝没有设计女性的性行为
satisfied to have sexual satisfaction
满意地拥有性满足感
and if you happen to be sitting here and
如果你碰巧坐在这里
believe that you
相信你
need to read intended for pleasure and
需要阅读意图的乐趣和
you need to learn your body better that
你需要更好地学习你的身体
is definitely not true the wife has the
妻子有这个绝对不是真的
same command and what is what is this
同样的命令，这是什么
obligation then the next point in the
义务然后是下一点
outline we're taught that this
大纲我们教会了这个
definition we're taught to give by the
定义我们被教导给予
definition of love we are called to give
爱的定义，我们叫做给
and I would just remind you again of the
我会再次提醒你的
definition of love from the last time
从最后一次定义爱情
that I spoke self sacrificial giving for
我说自己牺牲了
the betterment of another which leads to
另一个的改善，这导致
your true happiness that would imply
你真正的幸福这将意味着
sexual happiness also as you learn to
你也学会了性快乐
give first Paul warns us under point
首先， 保罗警告我们
point one underneath that first current
在第一个电流下面指出一个
first Corinthians 13 warns us that there
哥林多前书第13章警告我们那里
is a such a thing as selfish love it can
这是一种自私的爱情
look like it's giving but it's really
看起来像是在给予，但它确实如此
not giving when it has its own self as
当它有自己的时候不给予
the primary focus the greatest pleasure
主要焦点是最大的乐趣
is in giving the attitude behind that
是在给予背后的态度
should be it makes me happy to make you
应该让我很高兴能成为你
happy how can I serve you so how do you
我怎么能为你服务呢？你怎么样
know well guess what you have to talk
我很清楚你要说些什么
about it and if you're uncomfortable
关于它，如果你不舒服
talking about it that takes me right
谈论它，这让我很正确
back to the last session where I taught
回到 那里我教的最后一次会议
you need to talk about why you can't
你需要谈谈olor="#E5E5E5">，就是上帝
revealing truth just like he revealed
揭露真相就像他透露的那样
truth in the Bible and so we could use
圣经中的真理， 所以我们可以使用
both of those to counsel people that's
这两个人都是为那些人提供咨询
different because when an when a
不同，因为什么时候一个
professing unbeliever comes up with a
自称不信的人想出了一个
counseling system and they're telling
咨询系统，他们正在讲述
you to use this in counseling people at
你 在辅导人用这个
the crossroads of life but it is not in
人生的十字路口，但它不是在
conformity with what the Bible is saying
符合圣经所说的
about that that's neither the identity
关于那不是身份
of general revelation nor is it the
一般的启示也不是
purpose of general revelation the
一般启示的目的
purpose of general revelation is to
一般启示的目的是
convict people of sin and to reveal
使罪人定罪并揭露
enough truth through creation and
足够的真相通过创造和
through their conscience that they could
通过他们的良心，他们可以
seek God there's also special revelation
寻求上帝也有特别的启示
special revelation occurs only through
特殊的启示只能通过
the Bible the essence of special
圣经是特殊的本质
revelation is its focus on the purpose
启示是它关注的目的
and propitiatory work of Jesus Christ
和耶稣基督的赎罪工作
through special revelation that is to
通过特殊启示来实现
say by God's Word every elected person
用上帝的话说每个当选的人
in the church age comes to salvation
在教会时代来到拯救
according to first Peter 1:22 2:25
根据彼得前书1:22 2:25
special revelation is also God's chosen
特别的启示也是上帝的选择
vehicle for the progressive
进步的车辆
sanctification of Scripture I mean of
我所指的圣经成圣
Christians excuse me so understanding
基督徒请原谅我这么理解
that the Bible is God's means for
圣经是上帝的手段
revealing truth in our time is also an
在我们这个时代揭示真相也是一个
important foundation of biblical
圣经的重要基础
counseling so I bring these these two
咨询所以我带这两个
points of theology for your
你的神学要点
consideration because you'll probably
考虑因为你可能会
hear them used in
听他们用过
different ways than then how the
不同的方式比如何
scriptures reveal the truth about the
经文揭示 了真相
topics they encompass so Roman numeral
它们包含的主题如此罗马数字
six our conclusion what makes biblical
六，我们的结论是什么使圣经成为现实
counseling biblical I'll tell you
咨询圣经我会告诉你
biblical counseling is biblical because
圣经辅导是圣经的，因为
its purpose is to honor and glorify God
它的目的是荣耀和荣耀上帝
by accurately following the truths of
通过准确地遵循真理
God's eternal Word and only those truths
上帝永恒的话语，只有那些真理
in every aspect of the counseling
在咨询的每个方面
process including but not limited to the
过程包括但不限于
purpose of counseling our view of God
咨询我们对上帝的看法的目的
our view of man our analysis of the
我们的人我们的分析观点
problem our source of counsel our source
问题我们的律师来源
of truth the definition of the solution
事实上解决方案的定义
the means of change the guide for
改变指南的方法
communication and the guide for
沟通和指南
relationships within the counseling
在辅导中关系
ministry the Word of God is adequate for
神的话语就足够了
each of these things God tells us that
上帝告诉我们的每一件事
his word is his instrument to equip us
他的话是他装备我们的工具
in each of these things in our own lives
在我们自己的生活中的每一件事
and in our ministry to others may God
在我们对别人的事工中，可能是上帝
strengthen each of us to counsel
加强我们每个人的建议
accurately from his word in discipleship
准确地从他在门徒训练中的话语
relationships in informal counseling
非正式咨询中的关系
conversations and in the formal
对话和正式的
counseling setting
咨询设置